Finding aid to the Department of Mathematics Records CA.MS.00162
Smith College Archives
Department of Mathematics Records
1899-1989
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of Mathematics.
CA.MS.00162
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
1 website
This collection contains black and white photographs, meeting minutes, mid-year and final exam questions, course syllabi, and department announcements.
Biographical / Historical
The Mathematics Department at Smith College was established in 1894.
Scope and Contents
The Mathematics Department records contain materials describing the department's courses as well as its Mathematics Club. Types of materials include black and white photographs, meeting minutes, mid-year and final exam questions, course syllabi, and department announcements.
Related Material
Researchers should also view: 42. Faculty and 90A-129. Departmental files, 1935-1970 [unprocessed/portions restricted]
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Smith College. Dept. of Mathematics.
- General, 1915-16; 1929; 1930s-40s; 1960s-90s (Box 1167, Folder 1)
- Clubs, 1938; 1953; undated (Box 1167, Folder 2)
- Mathematics Club-Constitution, By-laws, Minutes, 1899-1919 (Box 1167, Folder 3)
- Mathematics Club-Minutes, 1919-1928 (Box 1167, Folder 4)
- Mathematics Club-Minutes, 1928-1938 (Box 1167, Folder 5)
- Mathematics 12, 1900-1910 (Box 1167, Folder 6)
- Courses-Math 102, 1976; 1978 (Box 1167, Folder 7)
- Courses-Math 103, 1977-78 (Box 1167, Folder 8)
- Courses-Math 104, 1976-78 (Box 1167, Folder 9)
- Courses-Math 110B, 1956; 1979-80 (Box 1167, Folder 10)
- Courses-Math 115, 1978 (Box 1167, Folder 11)
- Courses-Math 121, undated (Box 1167, Folder 12)
- Courses-Math 122, undated (Box 1167, Folder 13)
- Courses-Math 202, 1976 (Box 1167, Folder 14)
- Courses-Math 215, 1978 (Box 1167, Folder 15)
- Courses-Syllabi, 1920s-50s; 1977 (Box 1167, Folder 16)
- Photographs, 1957-58; early 1960s; 1980s (Box 1167, Folder 17)
- Department of Mathematics website, first captured Dec 15, 2015; 1 linear feet
  Scope and Contents
  The website of the Mathematics Department at Smith College includes information on faculty, courses, the major and minor, news, events, and resources for students. The website was captured several times from 2015 to 2017, and is now captured annually as part of the entire Smith College website.